Égard, or the lockscreen here is the screen that the user sees when the power button is placed to unlock
the phone.
So in this case, the user has enabled their security and when the user presses the power button, the
screen is switched off.
So when the user pressed, the power button again shows this particular window.
And when the user swipes up, it shows this pattern and this pattern is actually implemented by the
key guard on the lock screen.
So now the user can give the button and it allows to log in.
So this security is actually implemented within the system.
Your.
He got murdered.
So let's look in detail how this is implemented and how the key card is loaded.
Let's have a look at the logs first.
So in them letter, I will power the emulator off.
So when I power off the emulator and see that the System UI key guard is handling that case, see the
key guard view mediator ease the class which handles that.
Now let's clear it off.
And then when I power on again backing a new mediator class which is coming under control, Android
System UI is handling it.
So now let me log in.
In this case, the user has set the pattern match as the security mechanism.
So let me log in now.
So I am now in the lounge, a screen that can be seen from the logs.
The keynote new mediator on the system looking at classes are responsible to handle this particular
use case.
And these he got glasses, which is responsible to show this pattern match screen, even if the user
has selected PIN code as the security mechanism.
And then it's again the same key guard versus which handles that.
So we will look deeper into that shortly.